# **Rushi Patel**

# 

#### Summary

Professionally trained and Oracle Certified Java Associate with almost 4 years of work experience in the IT industry. Developer and mentor at the Google Developer Student Club at Dalhousie University. Dedicated speaker skilled in influencing students through effective teaching sessions on the topics of my interest.

#### **Technical Skills**

Languages: Java, C#, Python, Gherkin, HTML5, CSS3

Databases: SQL (MySQL), MongoDB, Firebase, DynamoDB, Graph DB(Neo4j)

Frameworks/Libraries: Selenium WebDriver, Junit, NUnit, Springboot, JPA Hibernate, BDD Specflow, Spring MVC, React.js, Node.js, Material UI, Flask, ASP.NET

Tools and Technologies: AWS (EC2, Cognito, SNS, SQS, API Gateway, Lambda, S3, Lex, Secret Manager, VPC, RDS Aurora), Docker, JSON, RESTful API, Git, CI/CD, IntelliJ, VS Code, GCP, Postman, Jenkins, Jira, SonarQube, Designite

#### **Education**

Master of Applied Computer Science

Dalhousie University

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering

Gujarat Technological University (CGPA: 8.09)

September 2021 – Expected May 2023 Halifax, NS, Canada

> July 2013 – June 2017 Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India

> > April 2022 - Present

# Experience

### Teaching Assistant – CSCI 3130 Software Engineering

Faculty of Computer Science, Dalhousie University

 Involved in the development of new material for department courses by contributing to the creation of appropriate teaching materials to ensure that content and delivery methods satisfy learning objectives.

- Conducted labs for Test-driven development, Solid Principles, Design Patterns, Code Smells and Git workflow.
- Provided timely and frequent feedback to students, fostering an environment of open communication and interest in discovery.

QA Engineer September 2020 – July 2021

Ness Technologies

Mumbai, India

- Configuring **SonarQube** and **SauceLabs** for executing scripts in parallel and cross browser testing and utilizing SonarQube for automated static code analysis.
- Developed a standalone application in Java to compare and list files (with details of files) from different
  AmazonS3 servers using AWS SDK and generate comparison report.

**Associate Consultant** 

June 2020 – September 2020

Mumbai, India

- Designed and implemented the automation framework of Chubb small commercial marketplace application by using **Selenium WebDriver**, **NUnit**.
- Followed agile methodology and implemented clean code practices, **SOLID** principles, and **Test-Driven Development** using **BDD Specflow**.

# Sr. Software Engineer

Capgemini

Capgemini

October 2017 – June 2020

Mumbai, India

- Deploying the code in test as well in production environments with an added responsibility to merge the code using **Tortoise SVN/Bitbucket**.
- Teamed up with other developers to plan, design, and develop the service now application using **Java** in a financial domain project Synchrony Financial Bank.
- Responsible for creating controllers and services to get response using **Spring MVC** Framework and **Hibernate**.

# **Projects | More Projects on GitHub**

Igloodoor - Complete Password Security

- Planned, designed, developed, and deployed a responsive cloud-based web application that handles complete password management that ensures the safest password by increasing the average password security by 65% in an agile environment.
- Used AWS services (Cloud Formation, Cognito, EC2, S3, VPC, Lambda, RDS, API Gateway) and integrated these services to run the application on AWS infrastructure.

# Smarticle – Smart Article Application

Led an agile team to plan, design, develop and deploy a responsive web application that lets users to create, display, follow articles based on users' preference using **Springboot**, and **JPA**.

- Built **RESTful APIs** to interact with **Twitter** to get real time tweet data of the articles using **Twitter 4j** and utilized **JWT** for user authentication.
- Created and maintained integration pipeline in **Heroku** and **GitHub** for **CI/CD**. Managed source code using **Git** version control and adhered **Git Flow** branching strategy for on-time release.

# Multi-Cloud based Serverless Hotel Reservation System

College Champion – Soccer

Built serverless application using multi-cloud deployment model, and backend-as-a-service (BaaS).

2014-2017

- Used **GCP** as well as AWS services to implement features like room booking, food ordering, review feature, chatbot, chat communication, and application usage analytics to the admins.
- The team implemented services like Cognito, Firebase authentication, DynamoDB, Lambda, Lex, GCP Pub/Sub, GCP AutoML and Elastic BeanStalk to build the application.

#### **Achievements** Certifications Oracle Certified Associate Java Professional Customer Delight Award – Capgemini 2019 2018 Rising Star Award - Capgemini ITIL Foundation 2019 2018 Star of the month – Capgemini 2020 CPR, First Aid and AED 2022 2013-2015 University Champion – Table Tennis State Champion – Table Tennis 2014-2015